Neighbors, Inc. 110 110
Stage
Neighbors, Inc. Collection
1958-1990
Stage
110
34 linear feet; 34 boxes
The Neighbors, Inc. was founded in 1958 to promote integration in the Upper Northwest Washington, DC neighborhoods of Brightwood, Shepherd Park, and Takoma. Later, it expanded such efforts to all neighborhoods in Ward 4. Among the documents are administrative files, Advisory Neighborhood Commission files, Board of Directors files, budget and finance files, clippings, correspondence, membership meeting files, newsletters, pamphlets, real estate files, and information pertaining to events such as the Art and Book Festival.
Biographical / Historical
The Neighbors, Inc. was founded in 1958 to promote integration in neighborhoods in the Upper Northwest Washington, DC neighborhoods of Brightwood, Manor Park, Shepherd Park, and Takoma. Later, efforts were expanded to include all neighborhoods in Ward 4. Northwest Washington Neighbors, Inc. was founded by a group of activists committed to integration and fair housing. The activists had worked with a similar group in Southeast DC. With the help and advice of the SE Neighbors, Inc., they formed the organization that foucused the attention of city officials and the local press on their communities and demonstrated the difficulty in fighting the forces that threatened to destroy their neighborhoods. After schools desegregated with the 1954 U.S. Supreme Court Brown vs. Board of Education decision, there was a "white flight" to the suburbs. This mass movement was encouraged by unscrupulous real estate agents who threatened to purchase houses at low prices by falsely warning residents that their value of their homes would decline or their schools would deteriorate. Methods to accomplish this included renting small houses to large families and telling neighbors that the families had purchased the home. Neighbors, Inc. responded with a two-pronged approach. Using active committees, they found reputable real estate agents who would sell to all homebuyers (white and African American) without discrimination. Integration became more commonplace, the threat of re-segregation lessened, and real estate values continued to rise. The city opened access to secondary schools throughout the District, lessening the pressure to keep residents focused on neighborhood schools. The organization still exists today and has expanded its concentration on local politics, neighborhood revitalization, park and recreation engagement, and citizen engagement.
Scope and Contents
The Neighbors, Inc. Records document the day-to-day business of approximately fifty years of the organization. Among the documents are administrative files, Advisory Neighborhood Commission files, Board of Directors files, budget and finance files, clippings, correspondence, membership meeting files, newsletters, pamphlets, real estate files, and information pertaining to events such as the Art and Book Festival.
Neighborhoods; Associations, institutions, etc
- Series 1
  - Board of Education and School Board, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Education Commission, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Progress report on Title III Application, 24789 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Education, Title III ESEA, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Comments on proposed on Takoma School, 24722 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Passow Study Group Recommendations, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Statement re Urban League Proposal, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Statement, 25006 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Commissioners on 6 years Public Works Statement, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arts and Crafts Fair, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Real Estate General, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Appeal, form letters, quotes and fund raising, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fund-raising, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Fund-raising, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Fund-raising, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fund-raising, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Fund-raising, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fund-raising, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Resource Material Fund Raising, Printed matter, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - AandBF, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American light Opera Company, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Joet Thurber, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Benefits (children), Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Appeal form letter, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Contributions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Contributions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Contributions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Contributions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Resource material fund raising printed matter, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Suggestions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Solicitation lists of names, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Appeal list, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Ballet Folklorico, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Fundraising (15 files), 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Affiliated Groups, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Public schools, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Manor Park, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Neighborhood Councils, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Neighborhood Councils, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Manor Park Neighborhood, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Board of Directors, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Brightwood Neighborhood, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Benign quota and planned dispersion, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Board of directors, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Annual meeting and Board seminar, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Community reception list, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Crime and delinquency, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Crime watch proposal, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Federation of Civic Assns. (assns.), Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Films and bibliography, Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Good Neighbor Pledge Campaign, Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Highways, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Grier Housing Report, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Inglewood Neighbors, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Integration in General Housing, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Institute for educational development, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Interviews w/community leaders, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Junior H.S. cite selection, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lamond Riggs Citizens Association, Takoma etc., Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ludlow Community Association, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Maps, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - National Associations f Intergroup Relations Officials, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - National Capital Clearing House for Neighborhood Democracy Associations, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - National Capital Planning Committee, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Senate District Committee, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Neighborhood Commons, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - State of Purpose, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Speeches, PR, Publicity and Promotion, Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Neighborhood planning, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper Publications, Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Neighborhood Planning Council, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Newsletter Publicity, Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Organizations in NI area, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Parking, Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Plan Takoma, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - President of the U.S., Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Request, Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Recreation Department (D.C.), Undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Redevelopment Land Agency, D.C., Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Shepherd Neighborhood, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Lists, Undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Housing Information Service, Undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Housing Referral letter, Undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Speakers, NI membership meetings, Undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Solicitors cards, Undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Social Services, Undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Summer fund events, Undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Supreme Court of U.S., Undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Takoma Blair, Undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Tours, Undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Takoma School, Undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Urban renewal office, D.C. govt., Undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - WMATA, Undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Urban review office, D.C. govt., Undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Workshops, Undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Lusaka List, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Arts and Crafts Fair Press Release, Undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - First Annual Dinner Board Mtg., 27061 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Extravaganza, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Arts and Books Festival, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Housing District Comm., U.S. Govt., Undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Open Housing and the Church, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Book and Art Festival cloth bag, Undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Arts and Book Fair(s) and other publicity, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Arts and Book Fair(s) and other publicity, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Arts and Book Fair(s) and other publicity, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Arts and Book Fair(s) and other publicity, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Arts and Book Fair(s) and other publicity, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Arts and Book Fair(s) and other publicity, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Arts and Book Fair(s) and other publicity, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Arts and Book Fair(s) and other publicity, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Arts and Book Fair(s) and other publicity, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Arts and Book Fair(s) and other publicity, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Arts and Book Fair(s) and other publicity, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Arts and Book Fair(s) and other publicity, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Arts and Book Fair(s) and other publicity, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Mailing lists, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Mailing lists, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Mailing lists, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Mailing lists, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Mailing lists, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Mailing lists, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Mailing lists, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Mailing lists, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Mailing lists, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Mailing lists, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 1967 Art and Book Festival (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Sponsors, Undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Committee reports, all years, Undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Lorenzo Jacobs, Undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Annual report meetings, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Atlantic Monthly, Undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Board of Directors correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Board meetings, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Board meetings, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Churches and Synagogues, Undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Churches and Synagogues - Baptist, Undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Churches and Synagogues - Catholic, Undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Churches and Synagogues - Jewish, Undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Churches and Synagogues - Methodist, Undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Churches and Synagogues - Presbyterian, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Regulations Committee, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Community Inventory Committee, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Directors report, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - D.C. Council members, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Student Field Work, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Membership Committee, minutes of meeting, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Monthly meeting minutes, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Organizing reports, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Intern, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - IRS, Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - NI publicity, Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Press releases, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Misc. D.C. Govt., Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Neighborhood Commons, Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Newspapers, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Newspapers, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Nominating Committee, Undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Police dept., D.C. govt., Undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Police dept., D.C. govt., Undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - President's Report Neighbors Inc., 1960 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Program and planning committee, Undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Resignations, Undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Testimonies by NI, Undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Affidavit for petition signers, Undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Crenshaw Neighbors, Undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Chicago Commission of Human Relations, Undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - D.C. Citizens for Better Public Education, Undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - D.C. Education Association, Undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - D.C. Health News and Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Capital East Gazette, Undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - D.C. Fed. of Civil Assns., Inc., Undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Health and Welfare Council, Undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Leadership Council for Metro Open Communities, Undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - League of Women Voters, Undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Met Washington Fair Housing Council, Undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Missouri Commission on Human Rights, Undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - National Committee Against Disc. in Housing, Undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - North Avondale Neighborhood Assn., Undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - NW Boundary Civic Assn., Undated (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - NW Parents' Action Group D.C., Undated (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - NW Washington Fair Housing, Undated (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Pittsburgh Human Relations Cmn., Undated (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Plans for Process, Undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - SE Neighbors, Undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - South Manor Neighborhood Assn., Undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Takoma D.C., Undated (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Urban League Newsletters, Undated (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Washington Center for Metropolitan Studies, Undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - West Mt. Airy Neighbors, Undated (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Charitable Solicitations Section, D.C. Dept. of Licenses and Inspections, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Annual Cabarets, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Arena Benefit, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Raffle, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, Arts and Crafts fair, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Program ideas, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Raffle, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Subscribing members, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Art and Book festival sponsors, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Festival Executive Committee, Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Art and Book Festival (18 files), 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Minutes of Book Committee, Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Real Estate Advertisements, Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Racial Designations, elimination of in ads, Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Advisory Committee, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Awards and Commendations, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Data, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Contact List, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - misc., 1958 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - A-Z, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1966 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Executive Secretary reports, Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - General Report of executive secretary, Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Foundation applications, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Foundation applications, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Foundation applications, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Foundation applications, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Foundation applications, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Funding information, Undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Community social action, Undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Memoranda, NI President, Undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Letterhead, Undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Misc., Undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Office supplies, machines and service, Undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Newspapers, Undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Printed program, Undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Publicity committee, Undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Recruitment, Undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Recruitment, Undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Request information, Undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Printing ideas, Undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Speakers, Undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Special notices, Undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Speeches, public relations, publicity and promotion, Undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Speech material, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Staff activities, monthly calendar, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - State of Purpose, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - State of Purpose, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Tax data, Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Training courses, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Volunteer lists, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Volunteers, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Chronological files, May-August 1967 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Chronological files, May-August 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Chronological files, May-August 1967-1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Chronological Files, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Chronological Files, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Chronological Files, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Chronological Files, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Chronological Files, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Chronological Files, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Chronological Files, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Chronological Files, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Chronological Files, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Chronological Files, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Chronological Files, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Chronological Files, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Access, Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Adams Morgan Demonstration Project, Undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Ad Hoc committee Housing Crisis, Undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Adults Education Association of Greater Washington, Undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - American Council to Improve Neighborhoods, Undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - ADA Associations, Undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - American Jewish Comm., Undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Baltimore Neighborhoods, Inc., Undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Stabilization Group, Undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Bolton Hill, Inc. Stabilization Group, Undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Brightwood Businessmen, Undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Catholic Interracial Council Associations, Undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Clinton Hill Neighborhood Council, Undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Committee on Civil Rights, Undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Conservation of Neighborhood Pamphlets, Undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Civil Rights Commission, Undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - D.C. Coalition of Conscience, Undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Friends Suburban Housing, Inc. Stabilization Group, Undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Health and Welfare Council of the NCAA, Undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Howard University, Undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Hyde Park-Kenwood Community Conference, Undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - International Visitors, Undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Lamond Riggs Citizens Assn., Undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Labor Unions Association, Undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Ludlow Community Association, Undated (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Maple Valley Neighborhood Assn. Stabilization Group, Undated (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Misc. Assns., Undated (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Misc. Stabilization Groups, Undated (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Sedgwick Neighbors Assn., Undated (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Modern Community Developers, Undated (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Park Hill Action Cmte. Stabilization Group, Undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - National Assn. of Intergroup Relations Officials, Undated (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - National Assn. of Social Welfare, Inc., Undated (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - NAACP, Undated (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing, Undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - National Capital Clearing House for Neighborhood Democracy Assn., Undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - National Cmte. Against Discrimination in Housing, Undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Real Estate and fair housing, Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - National Civil Liberties Clearing House, Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Protest Action Groups, Undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Suburban Maryland fair housing, Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Stabilization of Changing neighborhoods, Undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - University Neighborhood Council, Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - UPO, Undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Urban League Associations, Undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Washington Center for metropolitan studies, Undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Washington Fellowship House, Undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Washington Planning and Housing Assn., Undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - West End Community Conference, Undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Windsor Hill Improvement Assn., Undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Race Relations, Undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Housing - Financing and home inspection, Undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Sale of property, Undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Racially mixed housing articles, Undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Real estate reports of activities, Undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Real estate speculation counter proposals, Undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Code of Fair Real estate practices, Undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Anti-suburbs; pro-burbs., Undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Capahosic Housing Conf., 1965 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Clergyman, Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - House and Garden Tour, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Housing and Home Finance Agency, U.S. Govt., Undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Housing Information Service Comm., Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Open Housing legislation, Undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Open occupancy, Undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Open occupancy developments, Undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Prospective residents A thru G campaigns, Undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Negroes in the Suburban, Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Prospective residents H thru M campaigns, Undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Annual report lists, Undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - NCCHND and Govt., Undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Housing, General, Undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Real Estate Committee, D.C. Govt., Undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Real Estate Committee suggestions for improvement, Undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Prospective residents N thru Z, Undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Reports and Statement for NI on Fair Housing, Undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Statement of a hearing... re Fair Housing, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Statement of NI... re Tibia Island, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - SIMMs, 1977-1979 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Newsletter Ad letter, Undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Misc. items, January 1977-October 1979 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Misc. items, January 1977-October 1979 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Misc. items, January 1977-October 1979 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Misc. items, January 1977-October 1979 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Misc. items, January 1977-October 1979 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Misc. items, January 1977-October 1979 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Misc. items, January 1977-October 1979 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Misc. items, January 1977-October 1979 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Misc. items, January 1977-October 1979 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Misc. items, January 1977-October 1979 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Misc. items, January 1977-October 1979 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Misc. items, January 1977-October 1979 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Misc. items, January 1977-October 1979 (Box 11, Folder 35)